练习 1-16：个人练习。现在看看你能不能用同一个
Exercise 1-16. Individual Practice. Now, let's see what you can do with the same
句子，只通过把重音移到不同的词上来表达不同意思。我会告诉你
sentence just by changing the stress around to different words. I'll tell you
要表达哪种意思。听到提示音后，尽快说出这个句子，
which meaning to express. When you hear the tone, say the sentence as quickly as
然后我会为你说一遍。为了测试你的听力，我会随机重复
you can, then I'll say the sentence for you. To test your ear, I'm going to repeat
这些句子。试着判断我重读的是哪个词。答案
the sentences in random order. Try to determine which word I'm stressing. The
写在括号里，但除非真的需要，否则不要看。第一，
answers are given in parentheses, but don't look unless you really have to. 1.
表示他只是借了钱，并没有偷。
Indicate that he borrowed the money and didn't steal it.
我没说他偷了钱，也许他只是借了。第二题：表示你在否认自己说过他偷了。
I didn't say he stole the money. Maybe he just borrowed it. 2. Indicate that you're
钱。
denying having said that he stole it.
我没说他偷了钱，那完全不是事实。第三题：表示你认为他偷的是
I didn't say he stole the money. That's not true at all. 3. Indicate that you
钱以外的东西。
think he stole something besides money.
我没说他偷了钱，他可能拿了些珠宝。第四题：表示
I didn't say he stole the money. He may have taken some jewelry. 4. Indicate that
说这话的人不是你。
you were not the person to say it.
我没说他偷了钱，是别人说的。第五题：要表达的是，他并不是
I didn't say he stole the money. Someone else said it. 5. Indicate that you don't
偷东西的那个人。
think that he was the person who stole it.
我没说他偷了钱，我觉得是别人拿的。第六题：要表达的是，你并未
I didn't say he stole the money, I think someone else took it. Six, indicate that
没有直接说出口，但确实以某种方式暗示。
you didn't say it outright, but did suggest it in some way.
我没说他偷了钱，我只是暗示有这种可能。第七题：要表达的是，
I didn't say he stole the money, I only suggested the possibility. 7. Indicate
他可能偷的是另一笔钱。
that he may have stolen a different amount of money.
I didn't say he stole THE money, but rather some other money.